Finding Aid for Michael O’Brien sound recordings, 1987-1990
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Michael O’Brien sound recordings 1987-1990
O’Brien, Michael, 1943-
60 sound cassette tapes
0739 Aa 2
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Michael O’Brien (donor no. 9853 ) and came to the library in January 31, 2007.
No further additions to the collection are expected.
The collection is open to research. The researcher is, however, warned that since the interviewees did not sign release forms permitting the transfer of their interview conversations to the Bentley Historical Library, he / she must sign the O'Brien access statement (available from the reference archivist).
Michael O'Brien is a professor at the University of Wisconsin Center-Fox Valley, Menasha, Wisconsin. In 1995, he published a biography Philip Hart; The Conscience of the Senate (Michigan State University Press). In the course of his research, Professor O'Brien conducted numerous interviews (in-person and by telephone) with individuals who were personally acquainted with Senator Hart. In his book, he indicated that he intended to donate the taped interviews "at some future date" to a historical depository.
The Michael O'Brien collection of taped interviews consists of 60 cassette tapes conducted over the period of 1987 to 1990. Most of the interviews were conducted over the phone.
Subjects - Sound Recordings:
Hart, Philip A. (Philip Aloysius), 1912-1976.; O'Brien, Michael, 1943-
Contributors: Sound Recordings
Hart, Jane Briggs.; Woolner, Sidney H. (Sidney Henry), 1911-
Genre Terms:
Sound recordings.; Oral histories.
- Oral interviews made as part of research for Philip A. Hart biography
  The audio-tapes are listed alphabetically by interviewee followed by a tape number. Some tapes include more than one interview.
  - Bangert, Charles March 26, 1988 (Box 1)
    (tapes 1-2)
  - Bario, Patricia March 28, 1988 (Box 1)
  - Barrett, Richard January 25, 1989 (Box 1)
    (tape no. 1)
  - Beckham, William May 9, 1988 (Box 1)
    (tape no. 3)
  - Berthelot, Helen May 23, 1988 (Box 1)
  - Bickwit, Len May 2, 1990 (Box 1)
    (tape no. 4)
  - Briggs, Basil March 15, 1990 (Box 1)
    (tape no. 5)
  - Bronfman, Ann April 2, 1989 (Box 1)
    (tape no. 6)
  - Burns, Carolyn May 9, 1989 (Box 1)
    (tape no. 20)
  - Clark, John October 4, 1989 (Box 1)
    (tape no. 7)
  - Cohen, Jerry March 30, 1988 (part 3 only) (Box 1)
    (tape no. 8)
  - Conserva, Cammie May 23, 1988 (Box 1)
    (tape no. 9)
  - Cornman, John March 26, 1988 (Box 1)
    (tape nos. 10-13)
  - Cotterall, William July 5, 1988 (Box 1)
    (tape no. 16)
  - Courage, Ray May 13, 1988 (Box 1)
    (tape no. 15)
  - Crepeau, Richard October 8, 1986 (Box 1)
    (tape no. 17)
  - Fenlon, Edward October 16, 1989 (Box 1)
    (tape no. 18)
  - Ferris, Muriel March 26, 1988 (Box 1)
    (tape nos. 13-14)
  - Field, John March 20, 1989 (Box 1)
    (tape no. 19)
  - Fitt, Alfred April 28, 1989 (Box 1)
  - Friedman, Saul May 17, 1988 (Box 1)
    (tape nos. 21-22)
  - Hart, Adelaide March 2, 1988 (Box 1)
  - Hart, Ann March 26, 1988 (part 3 only) (Box 1)
    (tape no. 23)
  - Hart, Clyde August 8, 1988 (Box 1)
    (tape no. 24)
  - Hart, James May 31, 1989 (Box 1)
    (tape no. 25)
  - Hart, Jane April 1-2, 1989, September 28, 1989, November 6, 1991 (Box 1)
    (tape nos.26-34)
  - Hart, Vincent May 16, 1989 (Box 1)
    (tape no. 35)
  - Hart, Walter April 30, 1988 (parts 1 and 3 only) (Box 1)
    (tape nos.36, 42)
  - Hayden, Martin May 13, 1988 (Box 1)
  - Hickey, Francis April 4, 1988 (Box 1)
    (tape no. 37)
  - Howard, Milton February 15, 1989 (Box 1)
    (tape no. 38)
  - Jeffrey, Mildred May 31, 1988 (Box 1)
    (tape no. 39)
  - Kincaid, Barbara May 23, 1988 (Box 1)
    (tape no. 40)
  - Kleeman, Werner May 23, 1989 (Box 1)
  - Long, Wallace May 9, 1989 (Box 1)
    (tape no. 41)
  - MacMullan, Russell July 5, 1988 (Box 1)
    (tape no. 16, 48)
  - McCarthy, Eugene June 7, 1988 (Box 1)
  - McGarvey, William June 7, 1988 (Box 1)
    (tape no. 42)
  - McKnight, Leila March 25, 1988 (Box 1)
    (tape no. 10)
  - Moon, Charles February 23, 1989 (Box 1)
    (tape nos. 38, 49)
  - Muskie, Edmund July 13, 1988 (part 1 only) (Box 1)
  - O'Leary, Howard March 28, 1988 (Box 1)
    (tape no. 43)
  - Pertschuk, Michael April 13, 1988 (Box 1)
    (tape no. 44)
  - Pisor, Robert March 21, 1989 (Box 1)
    (tape no. 45)
  - Randall, Donald March 28, 1988 (Box 1)
    (tape nos. 1-2)
  - Rauh, Joseph, March 29 1988 (Box 1)
    (tape no. 46)
  - Richards, Eleanor March 20, 1989 (part 2 only) (Box 1)
  - Roth, Florence March 29, 1988 (Box 1)
    (tape no. 47)
  - Ryan, Richard May 19, 1988 (Box 1)
    (tape no. 48)
  - Simpson, William March 15, 1989 (Box 1)
    (tape no. 49)
  - Slattery, Paul May 16, 1988 (Box 1)
    (tape no. 21)
  - Smith, Ron September 23, 1986 (Box 1)
  - Sullivan, Cajetan June 15, 1989 (Box 1)
  - Sutcliffe, Lynn April 22, 1988 (Box 1)
    (tape no. 53)
  - Taylor, William January 26, 1990 (part 2 only) (Box 1)
    (tape no. 50)
  - Tucker, Donald April 11, 1989 (Box 1)
    (tape no. 51)
  - Wellford, Harrison May 3, 1988 (Box 1)
    (tape no. 52)
  - Welsh, William April 23, 1988 (Box 1)
    (tape nos. 36, 53-54)
  - Wides, Burton March 29, 1988 (Box 1)
    (tape nos. 55-56)
  - Williams, Nancy March 20, 1989 (Box 1)
  - Woolner, Sidney January 12, 1988, January 14, 1988, July 5, 1988 (Box 1)
    (tape nos. 57-58)